<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home on Sergio I. Mota</title>
    <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Home on Sergio I. Mota</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2018 18:56:13 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amigo20th.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Constellations: Reimagining Celestial Histories in the Early Americas</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/constellations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/constellations/</guid>
      <description>In our universe, the books are stars, represented as circles, or nodes.
Constellations were defined by a curatorial process, and later validated through an analysis of frequency of use of the most common words found in the curatorial labels (excluding articles, prepositions, and so on).
Constellations are depicted as graphs, or networks, and the relationships between books, that is, the connection between stars, are shown as edges. An edge between stars denotes a similar description based on tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different approaches to the detection of anomalies.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/presentacion_ame2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/presentacion_ame2020/</guid>
      <description>The presentation was made within the Virtual Colloquium of the Mexican Statistical Association (Asociación Mexicana de Estadística, AME) 2020.
The main topic of the presentation was the algorithms for the detection of outliers, different approaches were shown for this detection, each approach had its respective examples, which were:
  Statistical approach: Box-and-Whisker plot and MAD.
  Density approach: LOF and Isolation Forest.
  Approach through Machine Learning: Autoencoders and Self-Organizing Maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Detection of Outliers in In-vitro Cellular Gene Expression Data</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/poster_bio_mat_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/poster_bio_mat_19/</guid>
      <description>The poster was exhibited within the Fall School in Mathematical Biology (Escuela de Otoño en Biología Matemática, EOBM) 2019 that was assigned to Mérida, Yucatán.
The poster shows the results of the application of different methods to detect outliers in a set of vitamin D genes.
The dataset only had 3 attributes, which were:
  Retention intensity of the Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) at 8 hours.
  Retention intensity of the Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) at 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Segmentation of areas damaged by COVID-19 through isolation forest in lung images.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/pulmones_covid_iforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/pulmones_covid_iforest/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative research project, this seeks to segment the areas damaged by COVID-19 in images of the lungs. Segmentation will be done through Isolation Forest.
What is sought is to apply an outlier detection method to find the damaged areas in the lung, the purpose is to use a method that is not so computationally expensive and that serves as a guide for experts to perform evaluations more quickly.
Images of the damaged lungs were obtained by positron emission tomography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of a divorce prediction test website.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/divorce_prediction_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/divorce_prediction_test/</guid>
      <description>In this project we are going to do a logistic regression using a single neuron or also called a perceptron.
The data set to be regressed will be based on predictors of divorce.
This project was brought into production using Flask, Html, JavaScript, CSS and Heroku.
NOTE: This project is just for fun.
Link to page code: https://github.com/amigo20th/Predictor_divorcios_aplicacion
Link to the perceptron code: https://github.com/amigo20th/Regresion_Logistica_Divorcios</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MNIST dataset classifier using Support-Vector Machine.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/classification_svm_to_mnist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/classification_svm_to_mnist/</guid>
      <description>In this project we are going to make a classification using a Support-Vector Machine.
The data set to be classified will be MNIST, which is a set of images that represent handwritten numbers.
This project was made by the libraries: numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib and seaborn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution to the traveling salesman problem using the Eclectic Genetic Algorithm.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_salesman_problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_salesman_problem/</guid>
      <description>Python implementation of the Eclectic Genetic Algorithm to find the shortest route of 50 cities of the traveling salesman. problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclectic Genetic Algorithm [EGA] in Python with application in a linear equation.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_linear_equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_linear_equation/</guid>
      <description>In computer science and operations research, a genetic algorithm (GA) is a metaheuristic inspired by the process of natural selection that belongs to the larger class of evolutionary algorithms (EA). Genetic algorithms are commonly used to generate high-quality solutions to optimization and search problems by relying on biologically inspired operators such as mutation, crossover and selection.[1]
This code contains the implementation of a type of genetic algorithm, it is Eclectic Genetic Algorithm EGA[2].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Forcing Visits to use SSL</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2009 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/blog/force-ssl/</guid>
      <description>Intro Doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter whether it&amp;rsquo;s a CakePHP app for a client, your own personal CMS, or any other web based application. If your passing around passwords or other sensitive info you should really implement SSL. SSL provides 2 main perks to your visitors.
 First it encrypts all communication that flies across the web. This prevents curious or devious billies from getting your secrets. Secondly it ensures to the user that your server is in fact who it claims, and not a nasty &amp;lsquo;man in the middle&amp;quot; attack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Search Results</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/search/</guid>
      <description>This file exists solely to respond to /search URL with the related search layout template.
No content shown here is rendered, all content is based in the template layouts/page/search.html
Setting a very low sitemap priority will tell search engines this is not important content.
This implementation uses Fusejs, jquery and mark.js
Initial setup Search depends on additional output content type of JSON in config.toml
[outputs] home = [&amp;#34;HTML&amp;#34;, &amp;#34;JSON&amp;#34;] Searching additional fileds To search additional fields defined in front matter, you must add it in 2 places.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
