<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Sergio I. Mota</title>
    <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Sergio I. Mota</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 15:00:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Segmentation of areas damaged by COVID-19 through isolation forest in lung images.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/pulmones_covid_iforest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/pulmones_covid_iforest/</guid>
      <description>Collaborative research project, this seeks to segment the areas damaged by COVID-19 in images of the lungs. Segmentation will be done through Isolation Forest.
What is sought is to apply an outlier detection method to find the damaged areas in the lung, the purpose is to use a method that is not so computationally expensive and that serves as a guide for experts to perform evaluations more quickly.
Images of the damaged lungs were obtained by positron emission tomography.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creation of a divorce prediction test website.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/divorce_prediction_test/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/divorce_prediction_test/</guid>
      <description>In this project we are going to do a logistic regression using a single neuron or also called a perceptron.
The data set to be regressed will be based on predictors of divorce.
This project was brought into production using Flask, Html, JavaScript, CSS and Heroku.
NOTE: This project is just for fun.
Link to page code: https://github.com/amigo20th/Predictor_divorcios_aplicacion
Link to the perceptron code: https://github.com/amigo20th/Regresion_Logistica_Divorcios</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MNIST dataset classifier using Support-Vector Machine.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/classification_svm_to_mnist/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2020 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/classification_svm_to_mnist/</guid>
      <description>In this project we are going to make a classification using a Support-Vector Machine.
The data set to be classified will be MNIST, which is a set of images that represent handwritten numbers.
This project was made by the libraries: numpy, pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib and seaborn</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution to the traveling salesman problem using the Eclectic Genetic Algorithm.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_salesman_problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_salesman_problem/</guid>
      <description>Python implementation of the Eclectic Genetic Algorithm to find the shortest route of 50 cities of the traveling salesman. problem.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eclectic Genetic Algorithm [EGA] in Python with application in a linear equation.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_linear_equation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 12:41:05 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/projects/creations/ega_linear_equation/</guid>
      <description>In computer science and operations research, a genetic algorithm (GA) is a metaheuristic inspired by the process of natural selection that belongs to the larger class of evolutionary algorithms (EA). Genetic algorithms are commonly used to generate high-quality solutions to optimization and search problems by relying on biologically inspired operators such as mutation, crossover and selection.[1]
This code contains the implementation of a type of genetic algorithm, it is Eclectic Genetic Algorithm EGA[2].</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
