<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Publications on Sergio I Mota</title>
    <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Publications on Sergio I Mota</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2020 16:47:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Constellations: Reimagining Celestial Histories in the Early Americas</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/constellations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/constellations/</guid>
      <description>In our universe, the books are stars, represented as circles, or nodes.
Constellations were defined by a curatorial process, and later validated through an analysis of frequency of use of the most common words found in the curatorial labels (excluding articles, prepositions, and so on).
Constellations are depicted as graphs, or networks, and the relationships between books, that is, the connection between stars, are shown as edges. An edge between stars denotes a similar description based on tags.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different approaches to the detection of anomalies.</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/presentacion_ame2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/presentacion_ame2020/</guid>
      <description>The presentation was made within the Virtual Colloquium of the Mexican Statistical Association (Asociación Mexicana de Estadística, AME) 2020.
The main topic of the presentation was the algorithms for the detection of outliers, different approaches were shown for this detection, each approach had its respective examples, which were:
  Statistical approach: Box-and-Whisker plot and MAD.
  Density approach: LOF and Isolation Forest.
  Approach through Machine Learning: Autoencoders and Self-Organizing Maps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unsupervised Detection of Outliers in In-vitro Cellular Gene Expression Data</title>
      <link>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/poster_bio_mat_19/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amigo20th.github.io/publications/poster_bio_mat_19/</guid>
      <description>The poster was exhibited within the Fall School in Mathematical Biology (Escuela de Otoño en Biología Matemática, EOBM) 2019 that was assigned to Mérida, Yucatán.
The poster shows the results of the application of different methods to detect outliers in a set of vitamin D genes.
The dataset only had 3 attributes, which were:
  Retention intensity of the Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) at 8 hours.
  Retention intensity of the Vitamin D Receptor (VDR) at 24 hours.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
